Sons of Scotland Benevolent Association fonds
Simon Fraser University Archives and Records Management Department
- Glengarry Camp, No. 212 records, 1937 - 1989; F-192-4; 94 cm of textual records; Sons of Scotland Benevolent Association. Glengarry Camp, No. 212
  - Newsletters, correspondence, reports and other records, 1943 - 1981; F-192-4-4; 8 cm of textual records
    - Report: Glengarry Camp 212, Recording Secretary [report of camp activities, December 10, 1943 to November 8, 1968], 9 May 1969; F-192-4-4-0-7 (Archival box - standard 192-13)
    - Glengarry - assorted newsletters and correspondence, 1968 - 1981; F-192-4-4-0-8 (Archival box - standard 192-13)
    - United Scottish Societies Auditorium newsletters 1974, 1974 - 1981; F-192-4-4-0-9 (Archival box - standard 192-13)
    - Marshall Opening, member lists, secretaries lists, [correspondence, and District Committee by-laws, 1971], 1943 - 1980; F-192-4-4-0-10 (Archival box - standard 192-13)
- Lord Tweedsmuir Camp, No. 209 minute books, 1939 - 1997; F-192-5; 30 cm of textual records; Sons of Scotland Benevolent Association. Lord Tweedsmuir Camp, No. 209
  The Lord Tweedsmuir Camp, named after the then Governor General, was founded in the Kerrisdale area of Vancouver, and instituted on April 20, 1936. For honorary members, the initiation fee was two dollars, with an annual fee of three dollars, and for active members the initiation fee was eight dollars, with a monthly fee of fifty cents. The Camp met at the Canadian Legion Hall at 42nd Avenue and Yew Street until June 1960, and then at the South Main Masonic Hall on Main Street, until June 1987. In September 1987, the camp began meeting at 2146 W. 41st Avenue, and the Camp, which is still active, continues to meet at that location.
  Series consists of records relating to meetings and activities of the Lord Tweedsmuir Camp. Records include minute books with related papers, such as financial statements, District No. 16 Committee minutes (1951-1960), and Grand Camp minutes (June 1942). Minute books also include new member lists and rolls of camp officers. Minutes for the years 1947 to 1950 are missing.
  The records were donated to the Simon Fraser University Archives by the Lord Tweedsmuir Camp in one accession on December 22, 2003.
  - Minute book, 15 March 1939 - 15 February 1943; F-192-5-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 192-13)
  - Minute book, 15 March 1943 - 18 December 1946; F-192-5-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 192-14)
  - Minute book, 17 January 1951 - 17 November 1954; F-192-5-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 192-14)
  - Minute book, vol. 1, 15 December 1954 - 23 November 1960; F-192-5-0-0-4 (Archival box - standard 192-14)
  - Minute book (enclosures), vol. 2, 15 December 1954 - 23 November 1960; F-192-5-0-0-5 (Archival box - standard 192-14)
  - Minute book, January 1961 - 20 November 1964; F-192-5-0-0-6 (Archival box - standard 192-14)
  - Minute book, 15 January 1965 - 15 November 1968; F-192-5-0-0-7 (Archival box - standard 192-15)
  - Minute book, 21 February 1969 - 19 November 1973; F-192-5-0-0-8 (Archival box - standard 192-15)
  - Minute book, 18 January 1974 - 21 December 1979; F-192-5-0-0-9 (Archival box - standard 192-15)
  - Minute book, 18 January 1980 - 20 December 1985; F-192-5-0-0-10 (Archival box - standard 192-15)
  - Minute book, vol. 1, 17 January 1986 - 19 December 1997; F-192-5-0-0-11 (Archival box - standard 192-16)
  - Minute book (enclosures), vol. 2, 17 January 1986 - 19 December 1997; F-192-5-0-0-12 (Archival box - standard 192-16)
- Murray Camp, No. 215 minutes and related records, 1968 - 1975; F-192-6; 6 cm of textual records; Sons of Scotland Benevolent Association. Murray Camp, No. 215
  On October 23, 1968, a meeting was held at the Rod and Gun Club at No. 3 and Cambie roads in Richmond, for the purpose of instituting a new camp. The camp was named the Murray Camp, in honor of Camp Organizer Alex Murray, who had been an active member of the Sons of Scotland for thirty-two years. There were eighty-seven members accepted into the Camp at the meeting. The first Chief was Alex McKelvie, and the first Chieftain was W. Kane. The camp later met at the South Arm Community Center (March 1969 to February 1975), and then the Richmond United Church hall on Cambie Road. On June 13, 1975, a special meeting was held to discuss whether or not the Camp would disband, due to its declining membership and a perceived lack of membership support for the Executive. After a vote in favour of disbanding, the Camp was dissolved.
  Series consists of records relating to the meetings, activities, and membership of the Murray Camp. Records include a minute book (October 1968 to June 1975) and a corresponding meeting attendance register (May 1969 to May 1975). Minute book includes related papers, member lists, and rolls of Camp officers.
  - Minute book, vol. 1, 23 October 1968 - 13 June 1975; F-192-6-0-0-1 (Archival box - standard 192-16)
  - Minute book (enclosures), vol. 2, 23 October 1968 - 13 June 1975; F-192-6-0-0-2 (Archival box - standard 192-16)
  - Minute book [attendance lists for meetings], 1968 - 1975; F-192-6-0-0-3 (Archival box - standard 192-16)
- Royal Scot Camp, No. 172 records, 1895 - 1969; F-192-7; 52 cm of textual records; Sons of Scotland Benevolent Association. Royal Scot Camp, No. 172
  On August 19, 1895, members of the St. Andrews and Caledonian Society met in the Society's rooms on the Dunn Miller Block in Vancouver. Their guest for the evening was Captain D.M. Robertson, the Grand Secretary of the Sons of Scotland Benevolent Association. Robertson had come from Toronto with the intention of establishing a camp in Vancouver. By the end of the evening, thirty men had signed a petition to the Grand Chief, officers, and members of the Grand Camp for the creation of a subordinate camp in Vancouver. Robert Clark was elected as the first Chief, and John Johnstone as the first Chieftain. Five dollars was agreed upon as the initiation fee for members. At the next meeting, on August 29, the name Royal Scot was selected, and the name was formally adopted at the September 16 meeting. By December 21, 1899, the Camp had sixty-two members. Among the occupations listed for members between 1895 and 1899 were merchant, contractor, lumberman, physician, sailor, engineer, and policeman. The Camp is no longer active, but was in existence until 1969, at least.
  Series consists of records relating to the Royal Scot Camp. Activities, events and topics documented include the founding of the Camp, as well as Camp meetings, general activities, and finances. Records include minute books and related papers; financial ledgers and cash books; a report; and promotional material.
  The arrangement into sub-series was provided by the archivist according to type of material.
  - Minute books, 1895 - 1969; F-192-7-1; 15 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of minute books and related papers documenting the founding, meetings, and activities of the Royal Scot Camp. Minutes cover the years 1895 to 1899 and 1940 to 1969. Some books include lists of new and/or existing members, as well as a roll of officers. Related papers include a March 1969 "District Synopsis" for District No. 16.
    Files are arranged alphabetically.
    - Minute book, 1895; F-192-7-1-0-1 (Archival box - standard 192-16)
    - Minute book, 1896 - 1899; F-192-7-1-0-2 (Archival box - standard 192-17)
    - Minute book, January 1940 - October 1951; F-192-7-1-0-3 (Archival box - standard 192-17)
    - Minute book, December 1951 - 8 August 1956; F-192-7-1-0-4 (Archival box - standard 192-17)
    - Minute book, 12 September 1956 - 12 December 1962; F-192-7-1-0-5 (Archival box - standard 192-17)
    - Minute book, vol. 1, 9 January 1963 - 9 April 1969; F-192-7-1-0-6 (Archival box - standard 192-17)
    - Minute book (enclosures), vol. 2, 9 January 1963 - 9 April 1969; F-192-7-1-0-7 (Archival box - standard 192-17)
    - Minute book, 1965; F-192-7-1-0-8 (Archival box - standard 192-17)
  - Financial records, 1916 - 1944; F-192-7-2; 35 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of records relating to the Camp's finances. Records include Financial Secretary ledgers (1916-1944), and cash books (1917-1943).
    - Financial Secretary's ledger, 1916 - 1923; F-192-7-2-0-1 (Archival box - standard 192-18)
    - Financial Secretary's ledger, 1924 - 1927; F-192-7-2-0-2 (Archival box - standard 192-18)
    - Financial Secretary's ledger, 1928 - 1930; F-192-7-2-0-3 (Archival box - standard 192-18)
    - Financial Secretary's ledger, 1931 - 1934; F-192-7-2-0-4 (Archival box - standard 192-18)
    - Financial Secretary's ledger, 1935 - 1936; F-192-7-2-0-5 (Archival box - standard 192-19)
    - Financial Secretary's ledger, 1937 - 1938; F-192-7-2-0-6 (Archival box - standard 192-19)
    - Financial Secretary's ledger, 1939 - 1940; F-192-7-2-0-7 (Archival box - standard 192-19)
    - Financial Secretary's ledger, 1941 - 1942; F-192-7-2-0-8 (Archival box - standard 192-19)
    - Financial Secretary's ledger, 1943 - 1944; F-192-7-2-0-9 (Archival box - standard 192-20)
    - Cash book, 1917 - 1925; F-192-7-2-0-10 (Archival box - standard 192-20)
    - Cash book, 1926 - 1931; F-192-7-2-0-11
    - Cash book, 1931 - 1936; F-192-7-2-0-12 (Archival box - standard 192-20)
    - Cash book, September 1936 - December 1943; F-192-7-2-0-13 (Archival box - standard 192-20)
  - Promotional material, [196-?]; F-192-7-3; 2 cm of textual records
    Sub-series consists of a promotional Sons of Scotland Benevolent Association folder used by the Royal Scot Camp.
    - Folder: Welcome! to the Sons of Scotland Benevolent Association, [196-?]; F-192-7-3-0-1 (Archival box - standard 192-20)